in this lesson
instead of expanding a single log into
multiple logarithms
we're going to condense
multiple logs into a single log
so this is the opposite of the last
lesson
so hopefully you've watched the last
lesson before this one
so we're going to write this as a single
log
now the ones that contain a positive
sign
will go on top so that's a and c so it's
going to be a times c
on top
now b has a negative in front of it so
it's going to go on the bottom
so it's going to be log
ac over b
let's try another example
2 log a
plus
5 log b
minus 7 log c
so how can we express
this expression as a single log
the first thing we need to do
is move the coefficient
to the exponent position
so this is going to be log
a squared plus
log b to the fifth
minus
log c to the seventh
now we can write a single log
a and b both have a positive sign in
front so they're going to be on top a
squared b to the fifth
c has a negative sign in front of it
so c to the seventh is going to be on
the bottom
therefore this is the answer
try this one
one third
log a
minus two thirds
log b
plus
one fourth
log c
minus four over five
log d
so first so let's move all of the
coefficients
to the exponent position
so this is equal to log a
raised to the 1 3
minus log b
to the two thirds plus
log c
to the one fourth
minus log d
to the four fifths
and now let's write it as a single log
so a and c both have a positive sign
so it's going to be a to the one-third
c to the one-fourth on top
now b and d both contain a negative sign
in front of the log
so they're going to go on the bottom b
to the two thirds
and then d to the four fifths
so you can leave your answer like this
or you can convert it back
into radical form
so you can write it like this as well
the cube root of a
times the fourth root of c
divided by the cube root of b squared
times the fifth root of d to the fourth
you